Guide to the John Steinbeck Collection, 1902-1979 M0263
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Articles about John Steinbeck's life, 1970-1981 (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Articles about John Steinbeck's life, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 6)
- John Steinbeck's Travels to Finland (Box 13, Folder 7)
- John Steinbeck's Travels to Finland (Box 13, Folder 8)
- Cultural Exchange behind the Iron Curtain, Polish Press, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 1)
- Cultural Exchange behind the Iron Curtain, Polish Press, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 2)
- Cultural Exchange behind the Iron Curtain, Soviet Press, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Cultural Exchange behind the Iron Curtain, Soviet Press, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Cultural Exchange behind the Iron Curtain, Berlin, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 5)
- Cultural Exchange behind the Iron Curtain, Leningrad, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 6)
- Cultural Exchange behind the Iron Curtain, Vienna, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 7)
- Cultural Exchange behind the Iron Curtain, Kiev, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 8)
- Cultural Exchange behind the Iron Curtain, American Press, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 9)
- Cultural Exchange behind the Iron Curtain, Tbilisi, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 10)
- Cultural Exchange behind the Iron Curtain, correspondence, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 11)
- Cultural Exchange behind the Iron Curtain, articles (Box 14, Folder 12)
- Cultural Exchange behind the Iron Curtain, articles (Box 14, Folder 13)
- Cultural Exchange behind the Iron Curtain, articles (Box 15, Folder 1)
- Southeast Asian Trip (Box 15, Folder 2)
- Legal Papers (Box 15, Folder 3)
- Invitations (Box 15, Folder 4)
- Steinbeck at the White House (Box 15, Folder 5)
- Steinbeck at the White House (Box 15, Folder 6)
- Sonate at Tortilla Flat (Box 15, Folder 7)
- Congratulations for Nobel Prize (Box 15, Folder 8)
- Congratulations for Nobel Prize (Box 15, Folder 9)
- Scrapbook by Gylendal (Box 15, Folder 10)
- Commemorative stamps, poster (Box 15, Folder 11)
- Photographs, John Steinbeck, alone, 1935-1963 (Box 15, Folder 12)
- Photographs, John Steinbeck with others, 1938-1954 (Box 15, Folder 13)
- Photographs, John Steinbeck with others, 1954-1962 (Box 15, Folder 14)
- Photographs, John Steinbeck with others, 1962-1963 (Box 16, Folder 1)
- Photographs, John Steinbeck with others, 1963 (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Photographs, John Steinbeck with others, 1963 (Box 16, Folder 3)
- Photographs, John Steinbeck with others, 1963 (Box 16, Folder 4)
- Photographs, John Steinbeck with others, 1965-1967, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 5)
- Photographs without John Steinbeck, 1937-1962 (Box 16, Folder 6)
- Photographs without John Steinbeck, artwork of John Steinbeck (Box 16, Folder 7)
- Steinbeck Programs and Steinbeck Foundation (Box 16, Folder 8)
- Steinbeck Programs and Steinbeck Foundation (Box 16, Folder 9)
- Steinbeck week in Salinas, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 10)
- Theater and movie programs; articles (Box 16, Folder 11)
- Theater and movie programs; articles (Box 16, Folder 12)
- Captions for exhibit, 1975 and 1978 (Box 16, Folder 13)
- Steinbeck: A Life in Letters, press coverage, publicity (Box 16, Folder 14)
- Articles about Elaine Steinbeck (Box 17, Folder 1)
- Steinbeck Associates and Family (Box 17, Folder 2)
- Steinbeck Country material (Box 17, Folder 3)
- Steinbeck Country material (Box 17, Folder 4)
- Steinbeck Country material (Box 17, Folder 5)
- Steinbeck Country material (Box 17, Folder 6)
- Steinbeck Country material (Box 17, Folder 7)
- Steinbeck Country material (Box 17, Folder 8)
- Bookseller Catalogues, etc. (Box 17, Folder 9)
- Bookseller Catalogues, etc. (Box 17, Folder 10)
- Stanford University (Box 17, Folder 11)
- Other Steinbeck Collections (Box 17, Folder 12)
- Movie Stills (Box 17, Folder 13)
- Negatives: Ed Rickett's Study (Box 17, Folder 14)
- Ledger: Manuscript fragment, "The God in the Pipes" (1939) [see Working Days]. Includes "Mrs. Van Deventer and Daughter," "The Maltbys," "The Lopez Sisters," "The Deserted Farm," "Miss Morgan," "Raymond Banks," "John Whiteside and His House," "Pat Humbert," "Second Version," fragment about a boy named Mizpah. (Box 18)
- Cannery Row: collection overview (Box 19, Folder 1)
- Cannery Row: Proof copy; 1st edition (Box 19, Folder 2)
- Cannery Row: galley proofs (Box 19, Folder 3)
- Cannery Row: corrected typewritten manuscript (197 pp.) (Box 19, Folder 4)
- Cannery Row: Original pencil manuscript (143 pp.) (Box 19, Folder 5)
- Manuscript: "The Boss in the Pipes," Cannery Row fragment (Box OS 1, Folder 1)
- Photographs of Steinbeck (includes original Sonya Noskowiak portrait, 1936) (Box OS 1, Folder 2)
- Lobby cards: East of Eden, The Red Pony, The Moon is Down, Tortilla Flat, A Medal for Benny (Box OS 1, Folder 3)
- Posters and Lithographs: John Steinbeck's America in Newsday; John Steinbeck's Letters to Alicia in Newsday; Lithograph of dustjacket of Grapes of Wrath, 1980 (Box OS 1, Folder 4)
- Monterey Peninsula Herald, "Good Guys and Bad Guys," by John Steinbeck, 10 March 1955; Monterey Bay Aquarium poster, 1979 (Box OS 1, Folder 5)
- "Steinbeck: His Life, Land, and Works," educational material (incl. audiocassette and negatives) (Box OS 1)